Guide to the Robert College records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Records of the Trustees
  - Subseries II. 1: Christopher Robert
    - Correspondence to Merriman concerning sale of property owned by Robert at Lookout Mountain, Tennessee, 1886-1887 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - General correspondence to Merriman, 1887-1898 (Box 8, Folder 19 to 26)
    - Correspondence to D.B. Coe from Milton Badger, 1869-1870 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence to D.B. Coe from Robert, 1870-1876 (Box 9, Folder 28 to 29)
    - Correspondence Hamlin/D.B. Coe (typewritten) re Hamlin's relationship with college, 1878-1880 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence to D.B. Coe from Hamlin, 1879-1880 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence to William A. Booth from Washburn, 1880 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - General correspondence to Jacob D. Vermilye, treasurer, 1879-1880 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence to D.B. Coe from Washburn, 1879-1880 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence to D.B. Coe, Merriman and others from Washburn, 1885- 1889 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence to D.B. Coe and Merriman from Washburn, 1890-1892 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence to D.B. Coe from Badger, 1874, 1876 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence to D.B. Coe from Van Millingen, 1879 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence Booth/D.B. Coe, 1879-1880 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - General correspondence to D.B. Coe and Grosvenor, 1879-1880 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence to D.B. Coe from Grosvenor, 1880 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - General correspondence to D.B. Coe, 1879-1890s (Box 9, Folder 42 to 44)
    - General correspondence to Booth, 1880s-1905 (Box 9, Folder 45 to 46)
    - Caleb Gates to trustees re acceptance of presidency, 1902 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - General correspondence to John S. Kennedy, 1899-1901 (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - General correspondence to Cleveland H. Dodge, 1899 (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Report submitted to RC trustees by D.B. Coe (announces resignation of Washburn), 1903 (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Reports to the trustees submitted by D.B. Coe, 1903 (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Correspondence to Kennedy from Gates, 1905 (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - Special report to the trustees on the physical conditions of property and buildings at RC campus prepared by Gates and Alfred D. Hamlin, 1909 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Subseries II.2: General
    - Address of Gates to the trustees, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence Dodge/Gates, 1914-1919 (Box 10, Folder 2 to 10)
    - RC Library statement prepared for the Library Committee of RC trustees, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Reports on farm prepared for trustees, 1927-1932 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Report on visit to Turkey re merger of ACG and RC [author unknown], 1930 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Library account, financial statements, 1932-1934 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence to Henry Sloane Coffin and notes of an interview [interviewee unknown], 1935 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence Walter Wright/Bayard Schieffelin, 1935-1938 (Box 10, Folder 16 to 18)
    - Report of Survey of Near East College Association Office submitted by the Advisory Committee on Administration, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Memorandum re proposed American college for Hungary, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Statements re Robert College prepared by Floyd Black 1947 and Harold Scott, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Series III: Records of the President
  - Subseries III.1: Cyrus Hamlin
    - General correspondence to Hamlin, 1860-1869 (Box 11, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Letters from Washburn to his "father" (Hamlin), 1862-1864 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Letter written by Sir A. Bulwer declining invitation to attend opening of Robert College, 1863 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence to Hamlin re negotiations for purchase of land, 1863- 1864 (Box 11, Folder 5 to 6)
    - "Extracts from Hamlin's letters respecting a new professor", 1864 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence to Hamlin from Robert, 1864 (Box 11, Folder 8 to 11)
    - Correspondence to Hamlin from Robert, 1865 (Box 11, Folder 12 to 16)
    - Hamlin letter to Reverend Wood of the American Board (mainly about the Chernaud affair), 1865 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence to Hamlin from his nephew and sister, 1865 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence to Hamlin from Robert, 1866 (Box 11, Folder 19 to 20)
    - Letter from John P. Brown to Hamlin on U.S. involvement in purchase of land for the college, 1866 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Hamlin, notebook, Bebek, 1867 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence to Hamlin from Robert, 1867 (Box 11, Folder 23 to 25)
    - Correspondence re negotiations for property (includes letters to Hamlin from Brown), 1868 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Inventory of college property, 1868 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Letter to Hamlin conferring the Irade, 1868 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Hamlin's interpretation of the Irade, 1868 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Hamlin, memos to the trustees, includes "On the Presidency of RC," and "On Keeping the Sabbath", 1868 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence to Hamlin from Robert, 1868 (Box 11, Folder 31 to 32)
    - Typewritten drafts of Hamlin's letters to his family, 1868-1880s (Box 11, Folder 33 to 34)
    - Correspondence to Hamlin from Robert, 1869 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Building diagrams drawn by Hamlin, 1869 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence to Hamlin from Robert, 1871 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - General correspondence to Hamlin (includes Long's acceptance letter, 1872), 1871-1872 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Letters from Amherst and Yale Colleges in support of Robert College, 1872 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Subseries III.2: George Washburn
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Robert, 1867-1876 (Box 12, Folder 1 to 23)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Robert, 1876 (Box 13, Folder 24 to 25)
    - Correspondence to Washburn and Long from Robert, 1877 (Box 13, Folder 26 to 30)
    - Letter from Hamlin to his "son" (Washburn), 1862 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - General correspondence to Washburn, 1864-1873 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence to his "son" and Mrs. Washburn from Hamlin, 1868-1869 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Robert College Prospectus and Curriculum translated into Armenian, Bulgarian, and Greek, 1871 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Grosvenor, 1871-1890, 1903 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence to his "son" and Mrs. Washburn from Hamlin, 1873-1876 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - General correspondence to Washburn re U.S. centennial celebration, 1875-1876 (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Long, 1875-1879 (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Washburn, "Copy of Agreement for Sale of Land to William Lew", 1876 (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - General correspondence to Washburn (includes two long letters from Robert Thomson), 1877-1878 (Box 13, Folder 40 to 41)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Stephen Panaretoff, 1877-1902 (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence to Long, acting president, from Robert, 1878 (Box 13, Folder 43 to 46)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Merriman, 1878-1879 (Box 13, Folder 47)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Ivan Slaveikoff, 1878-1902 (Box 13, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Van Millingen, 1878-1881 (Box 13, Folder 49)
    - Financial statements prepared by Washburn as president and treasurer, 1879-1880 (Box 13, Folder 50)
    - General correspondence to Washburn: includes letters from William B. Dwight on the role of his brother (Reverend James H. Dwight) in founding the college, 1879-1882 (Box 13, Folder 51)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Booth, 1879-1885 (Box 13, Folder 52 to 54)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from D.B. Coe, 1879, 1892-1893 (Box 13, Folder 55)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Long, 1880-1893 (Box 13, Folder 56 to 57)
    - Financial statements prepared by Washburn as president, 1882-1885 (Box 13, Folder 58)
    - Robert College Prospectus and Curriculum translated into Armenian, Bulgarian, and Greek, 1884, 1897 (Box 13, Folder 59)
    - General correspondence to Washburn, 1884-1888 (Box 14, Folder 60)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Booth, 1887-1900 (Box 14, Folder 61 to 64)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Van Millingen, 188-1902 (Box 14, Folder 65)
    - General correspondence to Washburn, includes an informative letter describing Dwight's relationship with the college, 1899-1890 (Box 14, Folder 66)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Kennedy 1890-1900 (Box 14, Folder 67 to 68)
    - General correspondence to Washburn 1891-1897 (Box 14, Folder 69 to 71)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Reverend Edward B. Coe 1895-1900 (Box 14, Folder 72 to 74)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Dodge 1895;1900-1903 (Box 14, Folder 75)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Olivia P. Stokes 1899;1902 (Box 14, Folder 76)
    - General correspondence to Washburn, 1900-1901 (Box 15, Folder 77)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Gates, 1900-1902 (Box 15, Folder 78)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Kennedy, 1901-1902 (Box 15, Folder 79 to 80)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from E.B. Coe, 1901-1904 (Box 15, Folder 81 to 84)
    - Correspondence to Washburn re engagement of Friedrich W. Kunick as a German tutor, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 85)
    - Letter to Washburn from John Hay, Secretary of State re the ransom of "Miss Stone", 1902 (Box 15, Folder 86)
    - General correspondence to Washburn, 1902-1903 (Box 15, Folder 87 to 88)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Gates, 1903-1904 (Box 15, Folder 89 to 90)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Kennedy, 1903-1904 (Box 15, Folder 91)
    - General correspondence to Washburn, letters from M. Hartley Dodge and Robert Ogden, 1905 (Box 15, Folder 92)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from Gates, 1905-1914 (Box 15, Folder 93 to 96)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from A.Schauffler on Washburn's resignation as treasurer of RC, 1914 (Box 15, Folder 97)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence to Washburn, [undated] (Box 15, Folder 98)
    - Washburn sermon; Luke 2:52, 1874 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Washburn sermon, 1875 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Washburn notebook, notes of sermons, 1876 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Washburn sermon, Matthew 9:9, 1877 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Washburn sermon, "Christ and Socrates", 1878 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Washburn notebook, "Spiritualism--A Lecture", 1878 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Washburn sermon, Second Sermon on Mr. Robert, 1878 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Washburn sermon, Luke 9:49-56 on Religious Liberty, 1879 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Washburn, Baccalaureate sermon, 1884 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Washburn sermon, 1884-1885 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Washburn sermon, "Inspiration," Minister's Club, 1885 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Washburn notebook, "Reflections on Religion", 1886 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Washburn sermon, Acts IV, 1888 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Washburn sermon, "Galations", 1891 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Washburn sermon, 1892, 1895 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Washburn reflections--autobiographical and Baccalaureate sermon notes, 1895;1903 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Washburn notebook, Baccalaureate sermon, 1899 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Washburn sermon, 1903 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Washburn notebook, Baccalaureate sermon, 1904 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Washburn paper delivered at Chicago entitled "The True Aim of Missionary Work", [undated] (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Washburn notes, "Christian Evidences", [undated] (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence to Washburn from his mother and wife, 1882, 1891 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Washburn pocket diary, 1868 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - "Dr. Washburn's Personal Recollections", 1856-1900 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - "Personal Recollections" (printed), 1876-1880 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Washburn lecture notebook; [earlier pages cut out], 1863 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Washburn lecture notebook, "Reason and Instinct", 1875 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Washburn notebook and final copy, "The Conference of Constantinople of 1876-1877 a Memorandum", [1877] (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Washburn notebook, "The Treaty of Berlin", [ca. 1878] (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Washburn notebook, "Bulgaria and the Bulgarians #1", 1879 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Washburn notebook, "Bulgaria and the Bulgarians #2", 1979 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Washburn lecture, "Eastern and Western Civilization", 1886 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Washburn lecture, "Lord Stratford at Constantinople" 1889 (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - "The Fate of the East" [Washburn?], 1891 (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - "Ancient Egypt," [Washburn?], 1898 (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - Washburn ms. of Fifty Years in Constantinople, chapters III, IV, V, [pub. 1909] (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - Washburn ms. of Fifty Years in Constantinople, chapters VI-X, [pub. 1909] (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - Washburn ms. of Fifty Years in Constantinople, chapters XIX-XXVI, [pub. 1909] (Box 17, Folder 38)
    - Washburn ms. of Fifty Years in Constantinople, chapter XXVII, [pub. 1909] (Box 17, Folder 39)
    - Washburn typescript, "The Dismemberment of Bulgaria", [ca. 1913] (Box 17, Folder 40)
    - "Memo on the Last Balkan War and the Present Situation", 1913 (Box 17, Folder 41)
    - Washburn notebook, "Development of the Eastern Question to the Crimean War", [undated] (Box 17, Folder 42)
    - Washburn notebook; "Observations on Russo-Turkish War and Treaty of St. Stefano", 1877-1878 (Box 18, Folder 43)
    - Washburn typescript, "The Motive for Education", [undated] (Box 18, Folder 44)
    - Washburn lecture notes, "The Three Revolutions and possible future of the Ottoman Empire," and "The Religious Aspects of the Revolution in Turkey", [undated] (Box 18, Folder 45)
    - Washburn lecture notes, "The Probable Future of the Ottoman Empire", [undated] (Box 18, Folder 46)
    - Washburn lecture, "The Genesis of Bismarck", 1883 (Box 18, Folder 47)
    - Washburn notebook, "The Russian People", 1885 (Box 18, Folder 48)
    - Washburn notebook, "Observations on the Turkish Sultanate", [undated] (Box 18, Folder 49)
    - Washburn, Baccalaureate notes, 1887 (Box 18, Folder 50)
    - Washburn, political notes [undated] (Box 18, Folder 51)
    - [Washburn?], "Address to the Freshman Class", [undated] (Box 18, Folder 52)
    - Tributes to Washburn on his Retirement, 1904 (Box 18, Folder 53)
    - Washburn notebook, "Vacation, 1907", 1907 (Box 18, Folder 54)
    - Speech delivered by C. Hadji-Kaltcheff, '72 before the National Assembly on the death of Washburn, 1915 (Box 18, Folder 55)
    - The Missionary Herald (contains an article on Washburn at the time of his death), 1915 (Box 18, Folder 56)
    - Notice of Washburn's death in The Outlook, 1915 (Box 18, Folder 57)
    - Memorial tribute to Washburn, 1915 (Box 18, Folder 58)
    - Washburn's Memorial Exercises as described in The Orient, 1915 (Box 18, Folder 59)
    - Washburn's will, 1915, 1927 (Box 18, Folder 60)
    - Memorial tribute to Henrietta Lorrain Washburn, 1928 (Box 18, Folder 61)
    - Washburn, article entitled "A Great Benefactor of Bulgaria," by P.M. Mateev, 1931 (Box 18, Folder 62)
  - Subseries III.3: Caleb Gates
    - General correspondence to Gates, 1919-1924 (Box 19, Folder 1 to 6)
    - Material re educational conference held in Beirut, 1924 (Box 19, Folder 7 to 8)
    - General correspondence to Gates (includes a description of trip to Ankara), 1925 (Box 19, Folder 9 to 11)
    - General correspondence to Gates, 1926-1928 (Box 19, Folder 12 to 14)
    - Correspondence George Huntington/Gates, 1928 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence Laurence Moore/Gates, 1928 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - General correspondence to Gates, 1929 (Box 19, Folder 17 to 18)
    - General correspondence to Gates, (includes a description of trip to Ankara), 1930 (Box 19, Folder 19 to 20)
    - General correspondence to Gates, 1931 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence to Turkish officials re regulations, and taxes from Gates, 1929-1932 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - General correspondence to Gates, 1932 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Tribute from faculty of RC on retirement of Gates, 1932 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Tributes and letters to Gates upon his retirement, 1932 (Box 20, Folder 25 to 26)
    - Speeches at farewell dinner for Gates, 1932 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Tributes to Gates, 1930s (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Gates, lectures [undated] (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Gates, college addresses, miscellaneous remarks, 1921-1925 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Gates, Baccalaureate sermons, 1904-1932 (Box 20, Folder 31 to 41)
    - Correspondence re recognition of RC by Greece, 1897-1937 (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence re recognition of Engineering School by Bulgarian Government, 1923-1933 (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence re recognition of RC in France, 1925-1933 (Box 20, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence re recognition of Engineering School by Turkish Government (recognized as a "technicum" but not granted full status), 1928-1933 (Box 20, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence re recognition of RC and Engineering School by Albania, 1928-1932 (Box 20, Folder 46)
    - Correspondence re recognition of RC by Rumania, 1929-1934 (Box 20, Folder 47)
    - Correspondence re recognition of RC professors as members of the American Association of University Professors, 1931-1932 (Box 20, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence re recognition of RC by Switzerland, 1932 (Box 20, Folder 49)
    - Correspondence re recognition of RC by Italy, 1933 (Box 20, Folder 50)
    - Letters to family from Germany and Turkey, 1880-1882 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Letters to family from the interior of Turkey, 1882-1885 (Box 21, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Letters to family and others from Mardin, Turkey, 1886-1890 (Box 21, Folder 4 to 6)
    - Letters from Mardin and Harpoot, Turkey, 1891-1901 (Box 21, Folder 7 to 8)
    - "Letters selected by Mrs. Gates and kept by her", 1896, 1918 (Box 21, Folder 9 to 10)
    - Letters to his brother (Herbert) and family, 1903 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Mary Ellen Gates's correspondence to her son, 1906-1907 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Letters to his wife and children, 1909-1912 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Letters to his sons during World War I, 1913-1916 (Box 21, Folder 14 to 15)
    - Excerpts from Gates's letters to his son, 1914-1922 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - "Education from the Student's Standpoint", 1917 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - RC: wartime and postwar journal, 1914-1928 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - "Education in the Near East", 1919 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - "Saving Armenia", 1920 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - "Reconstruction in the Near East", 1920 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - General writings on post-war reconstruction, 1920s (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - "The Educational Future of the Near East", 1920 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - A description of visit by Gates to the Caliph, 1923 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Excerpts from diaries of C.Gates, Jr. and Mrs. Gates, 1924 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Letters from Jerusalem and Beirut conferences, 1924 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Description of trip to Jerusalem and Beirut for conferences, 1924 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Essay on RC with photographs (photographs not in file), 1925 (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - General writings on education, [1925] (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - "The Usefulness of Education to the Individual and to the State", [1925] (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Articles on Turks under the Republic (typescript), 1926-1930 (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - "The New Turkish Nationalism" (photocopy), 1927 (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - Address delivered by Gates titled "The Independence Day of the Republic of Turkey", 1928 (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence to Lynn Scipio from Gates, 1932 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - General correspondence Gates, 1932-1934 (Box 22, Folder 2 to 7)
    - Correspondence Scipio/Gates, 1933-1941 (Box 22, Folder 8 to 9)
    - General correspondence Gates, 1934-1941 (Box 22, Folder 10 to 16)
    - Hagopian Fund, 1930s (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Hagopian Legacy, 1938-1940 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - General correspondence Gates, 1943-1945 (Box 22, Folder 19 to 22)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence Gates, [no date] (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Memorial tributes to Caleb Gates, 1946 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - "Friendly Religion" and "Language and World Unity", 1929, 1930 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - "The Balkan Conference", 1931 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - "The Reading of the Koran in Turkish", 1932 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - "The Turkish Caliphate", [undated] (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Copies of The Presbyterian with articles by Gates, 1940-1941 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Short essays for articles, 1940s (Box 23, Folder 30 to 32)
    - Political observations, miscellaneous, 1940s (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Published and unpublished writings, 1940s (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - World War II notes, 1939 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Sermons, 1904-1920s (Box 23, Folder 36 to 41)
  - Subseries III.4: Monroe, Wright, Black, Ballantine
    - General correspondence Monroe, 1932-1935 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence Walter H. Wright/Elias Riggs/ W.T. Van Dyck, 1935- 1939 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence to Huntington from Wright, 1935-1939 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence to Wright from George Huntington, 1936-1939 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence to Wright from Black (carbons), 1936-1942 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence to Black from Wright, 1936-1942 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence Wright/Gates/ Larwence Moore/Allin Dakin (bursar), 1937-1939 (Box 24, Folder 7 to 8)
    - Correspondence to Wright from Moore Gates, 1938-1939 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence Wright/Ambassador John V.A. MacMurray/Professor E.W. Kemmerer, 1938-1943 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence Wright/Schieffelin, 1939-1940 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence to Sherlock Hibbs, Stephen Duggan, and Dean Collins Bliss from Wright, 1940 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Wartime travel, general descriptions (includes a description of flight from Turkey to NY), 1940-1943 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence re wartime travel and hiring teachers (includes letters from U.S. government officials), 1940-1943 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Wright's notes, general correspondence, 1941-1943 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence to Henry Sloane Coffin from Wright, 1942-1943 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - "Observations on American Turkish Relations," Wright, 1943 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Memorial services for Wright, 1949 (Box 24, Folder 18 to 19)
    - Correspondence to Black from Wright, 1944-1946 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence to Wright from Black, 1944-1946 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence to Black from Eleanor Burns, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence to Black from Wright, 1947-1948 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence to Wright from Black, 1947-1949 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - RC general, includes memos on development campaign, funding from U.S. government and drafts of revised constitution, 1947-1948 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - RC general, 1948 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - "Perspectives for the Future", 1954-1955 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - General correspondence Ballantine, 1955-1958 (Box 24, Folder 22 to 23)
  - Subseries III.5: Annual Reports
    - Annual Report, 1866-1872 [combined, 1870-1871] (Box 25, Folder 1 to 6)
    - Report of the Director, 1873 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Annual Report, 1874-1882 (Box 25, Folder 8 to 15)
    - Annual Report, 1883-1889 [in letter form, 1888] (Box 26, Folder 16 to 22)
    - Supplementary report submitted by George Washburn, 1890 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Annual Report, 1890-1910 (Box 26, Folder 24 to 33)
    - Annual Reports, 1911-1940 (Box 27, Folder 34 to 43)
    - Annual Reports, 1941-1943 (Box 28, Folder 44 to 45)
    - Financial Report, 1943 (Box 28, Folder 46)
    - Annual Reports, 1944-1945 (Box 28, Folder 47 to 48)